# KATHLEEN WILSON

808 Bronson Avenue, Ottawa Phone: (647)631-3856 | Email: kmcwilson4@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathleen-wilson-2b2a8b54/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/kmcwilson">https://github.com/kmcwilson</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://kmcwilson.github.io/react-portfolio/">https://kmcwilson.github.io/react-portfolio/</a>

### **S**UMMARY

Future Full Stack Web Developer leveraging background in Education to provide insight into how users will interact with software programs and websites as well as how these programs will be perceived by the user. Extensive experience in learning systems within the School Board coupled with the knowledge of Full Stack Web Development in order to successfully work within the technical realm of an institution. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among peers and colleagues for being a dedicated worker, a quick-learner and for paying attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, MongoDB, GitHub, MySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, GraphQL, Object Oriented Programming, MERN

### **PROJECTS**

The-Tech-Blog https://github.com/kmcwilson/CMS-blog-site https://pacific-forest-66625.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full stack application that uses a content management system to run a Tech Blog site. The Tech Blog is built using MVC (Model View Controller) design.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: Express, Handlebars, Node, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, JavaScript, CSS3

# Travel-Buddy https://github.com/Aesthetic-Justice/Project2 https://intense-lake-37290.herokuapp.com/login

- Summary: Application renders activities in specific cities according to user input and allows users to add additional activities to specified cities.
- Role: Front end designer anTravel Buddy Website post route for user
- Tools: Express, Handlebars, Node, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, JavaScript, CSS

# Note-Taker https://github.com/kmcwilson/Express-Note-Taker https://still-wildwood-29248.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Application uses express routing and javascript in order to create a note-taking application for the user. Notes can be added, updated and deleted from the application.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: Node, Express, Javascript

### **EDUCATION**

### **Boot Camp Certificate: Carleton University**

Ottawa, ON (February 2023)

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL,OOP, ORM, PWA, NoSQL, Computer Science, MERN, State, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

## **Bachelor of Arts (Honours) - Carleton University**

Ottawa, ON

### **E**XPERIENCE

Teacher 2017 - Present Ottawa Carleton District School Board Ottawa, ON

A positive and driven English/Math teacher with 8 years' experience working with students in grades K-5. Passionate about engaging students on all levels, enhancing their social experiences by encouraging group lessons and learning. Talented in using different teaching methods to reach out to students, including physical demonstrations, drawn illustrations and visual presentations. Key Accomplishments:

- Implemented successful lesson plans for 50 students, maintaining a high class average throughout the school year.
- Collaborated with colleagues and administrators in order to deliver results in Mathematics and English

Server June 2022- Present
Cantina Gia Ottawa, ON

Served customers in a high-paced, high-energy, well-regarded casual fine dining establishment Key Accomplishments:

- Work with an average of 100 guests per day.
- Open communication with both front of house and back of house to ensure coordinated food and drink deliveries to customers in a timely manner
- Extensive knowledge of both wine and menu items and demonstrated ability to romance items to customers in order to build sales

Server 2018-2022
Pure Kitchen Ottawa, ON

Served customers in a high-paced, high-energy, local casual dining establishment Key Accomplishments:

- Work with an average of 100-150 guests per day.
- Open communication with both front of house and back of house to ensure coordinated food and drink deliveries to customers in a timely manner.
- Ability to effectively communicate with disgruntled customers securing their future business

Teacher 2015 – 2017 Spirit of Math Schools Toronto, ON

Worked with 8 separate classes with an average of 15 students per class. Demonstrated ability to deliver the curriculum successfully with proven results.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed 120 students and delivered an enriched mathematics program successfully.
- Students visibly improved in their mathematics ability within my program.
- Saw the needs in each of my students and diversified programming in order for them to achieve their diploma.